## RYAN BISHOP SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

J	217-556-3251	EMPLOYER TO-DO
$\succeq$	rdbishop06@gmail.com	APPLICATION EVAL.
$\bigoplus$	rdbishop19.github.io/	PHONE SCREEN  HIRING MGR. INTERVIEW
(7)	github.com/rdbishop19	IN-OFFICE INTERVIEW
in	linkedin.com/in/ryandanielbishop	FOLLOW-UP

### **PROJECTS**

### **DEBUG DOCKET**

Front-End Capstone

- + Software Bug/Issue Tracker
- + Time Management Tool
- + Developer Social Platform

**Debugging** is an important skill for any developer. But bugs can have a bad reputation, being **costly**, **stress-inducing**, and **annoying**. I built **DEBUG DOCKET** to shift that mindset by approaching bugs with a growth mindset through *healthy time* management, *helpful analytics* and *team engagement*.

- Single-Page Application built utilizing React Hooks with full CRUDfunctionality for tracking to-do list of bug tickets and auto-tracking time spent on each bug
- Automated timer utilizing time management Pomodoro® Technique for consecutive work/break periods with friendly reminders
- Find fellow developer colleagues and view & help with their reported bugs

github.com/rdbishop19/Debug-Docket

### 2048-game

Python Home Project

- + clone of my favorite mobile game
- + built in Python 3.7
- + objectives: get the 2048 tile, have fun

Before I joined *Nashville Software School*, I was teaching myself Python and needed a project to **test my abilities**.

### 2048 requires:

- nested array manipulation/mathematics
- state comparison
- display and formatting techniques
- directional move event-handlers
- game over/high score functionality

I decided this was perfectly suited for a Python pet project.

github.com/rdbishop19/2048-game

### **ABOUT**

I learned about **software development** working previously in a customer-facing technical role in the food production industry. This position introduced me to **Statistical Data Analysis**, **Regression Analysis**, **Machine Learning**, and programming and database management (**Python/SQL**).

Leveraging this technical experience and a decade of business experience, I transitioned into professional software development via *Nashville Software School*. I'm a **lifelong learner** and inspired by continuous improvement **principles**, software design **patterns**, and passionate **people**. Let's **solve problems** together!

### **EXPERIENCE**

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | Nashville, TN | Sep 2019 - Mar 2020

Full-stack 6-month web development program encompassing both individual and group project learning and experience in software design and production.

Tech Stack: Python, Django, SQL, React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Git, GitHub

#### **Group Projects:**

- Developed a personal dashboard single-page application to manage upcoming events, to-do lists, shared news articles, friends, and chat messages. This app encompassed 2 separate sprints, built first in Vanilla JavaScript, and again in React, both utilizing JSON-server for persistent data storage. I personally implemented UI/UX affordances for the Chat Messaging and Add a Friend features, and championed group-programming for the Authentication feature.
- Created an itinerary planner for visitors to Nashville to search restaurants, parks, meetups, and music concerts. I championed the **Eventbrite API** for fetching local event data, and also wrote reusable code for displaying result data across all 4 separate API endpoints and also for itinerary items. Built in Vanilla JavaScript with HTML and CSS and utilizing JSON-server for database management.
- Built a celebrity tribute to the fictional Office TV show character Pam Halpert (Beesly) using HTML, CSS, Flexbox, Visual Studio Code, Git, Github, and httpserver. I championed repeated practice of the Git/GitHub workflow with my teammates, as this was our first experience using both platforms.



# RUNNER | PUZZLE MAKER SONGWRITER | EAGLE SCOUT PIZZA LOVER | WORLD TRAVELER

### **EXPERIENCE CONTINUED**

### FIELD APPLICATION SPECIALIST

Perten Instruments (A Perkin-Elmer Company) | Aug 2013 - Sep 2019

Analytical instrument company providing solutions for food ingredient screening, formulation, process monitoring, and final product quality control.

**Data Science:** machine learning using regression analysis of spectroscopy data via third-party and in-house data analysis toolkits (**Unscrambler, MATLAB, SQL, Python, R**).

- I performed data-wrangling of customer spectroscopy data sets using Excel/Unscrambler software to match 3rd-party reference chemistry data
- I created **regression models** utilizing *supervised machine-learning* (Partial Least Squares Regression and k-nearest neighbors algorithms)
- I installed/updated predictive models on customer equipment to improve accuracy and provide QA/QC process control
- I worked directly with customers discussing ways to improve their current predictive models and process control
- I wrote custom scripts automating regression results reporting to provide a standardized customer report format
- I wrote **automation scripts** to improve data analysis/data cleansing workflow

**Technical Support/Customer Service:** installation, training, and troubleshooting of on-site analytical equipment and software, including near infrared (NIR) and rheology lab instruments, utilized for the functional and compositional analysis of grain, feed, food, flour, and seed products.

- I provided live phone/remote desktop customer support to troubleshoot database and application issues
- I gave on-site multi-day customer training of analytical equipment and software
- I provided follow-up support/documentation to customers

### **MEDICAL TECHNICIAN**

Memorial Medical Center | Springfield, IL | Nov 2010 - Aug 2013

- Surgical Pathology: I assisted Pathologists with preparing and processing surgical specimens
- Diener: I assisted Pathologists with performing autopsies
- Administrative: I created new documentation for new hires and to help improve work flow

### **EDUCATION**

### NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full-stack software development bootcamp | Nashville, TN | Sep 2019 - Mar 2020

### ILLINOIS COLLEGE

B.S. in Biology & Spanish | Jacksonville, IL | 2006 - 2010

### LITCHFIELD HIGH SCHOOL

Graduated Valedictorian | Litchfield, IL | 2002 - 2006